This is Trigun.
guitar solo
The Typhoon is currently
gaining strength and will be
passing approximately 30
miles away from New Oregon.
The gale is expected
to last until morning.
Please be advised that high wind warnings
are still in effect until further night.
So this is a Typhoon.
I've heard that one can be strong,
but I never dreamed it could
blow with this kind of force.
Yeah, you're right.
In fact, this one is so huffy,
she must be related to...
Mr. Vash!
Her name is Jacqueline, and...
Mr.
Vash, excuse me, but
may we have a moment...
to speak with you?
Please don't look for me, Vash.
Damn, he got us!
Either he's incredibly slippery, or he's
just gone completely out of his mind!
I can't believe he'd actually
go out in these conditions!
No problem, we'll find it. Huh?
I suspected he might try this, so when I
brought him breakfast earlier this morning,
I slipped one of these
into the food on his plate.
Oh, my gosh.
That's a transmitting device.
I'm amazed the company let
you have something like that.
Since I'm always messing up, the chief
gave it to me as a going-away present.
He says it'll keep anyone
from outwitting me.
Millie, I hate to tell you, but
that's nothing to brag about.
Look, look, he's really close by.
We're catching up already!
Yeah! Warmer! Warmer! Warmer!
Oh my god!
He changed into a cat this time! Millie!
Vash.
Vash!
Come on, Vash.
Stand up already.
Let's go!
Hey!
Don't be that way.
It's just you and me here.
We should at least try
to act like brothers.
Murderer!
Your whole life is a lie!
You killed Rem! The crew!
You killed them all!
Yeah, spectacular, huh?
They all die.
Except, of course,
for the fraction who will survive
because of Rem's incessant meddling.
Knives?
You...
You aren't even human!
Damn straight I'm not!
How dare you call me
those damn perfect things!
How dare you!
Never compare me to that!
You're nothing but garbage.
I will kill you all.
Only we will be left on this planet.
Rem!
Now, Bash, take care of Noss!
I know what I have to do, Rem.
I can't wait any longer.
It's time to face him.
I have to be ready.
Jacqueline's ankle should
pass near the Craggy Bluff,
blowing to the southeast
at exactly 1.22 p .m.
I'm counting on you, old chum.
If you're wrong about this, you crazy
old geezer, I'll haunt you to the grave!
I still feel like I'm having a freaking
heart attack every time I do this!
This thing's going ba-da-boom ba-da-boom!
I thought you were committing suicide!
Suicide?
I strongly disapprove of
suicide, it's just a...
huh?
Wolfwood?
What are you doing here?
First you're crying your eyes
out like an abandoned baby,
and then you're running
around jumping off cliffs.
What the hell's the
matter with you anyway?
I'm visiting.
Say what?
I'm visiting the folks.
Yeah, right. What do they have?
A summer cottage in the sky?
I'm really getting sick of your lies.
Huh?
Hey, what the hell's that?
Just what it looks like.
It's a ship that didn't
quite crash 130 years ago.
This is unbelievable.
Who'd have known that the lost
technology was still preserved like this?
Wait, did you say you're
visiting your folks?
Does that mean people are
actually living up here?
I think that you'll be their first
house guest to visit in over 20 years.
Mr.
Legato, it has happened as expected.
He has made his move.
Also, the last stampede appears to
be working with the Minister Clan.
I suspect this man is...
Never mind him.
Your task will remain the
same no matter who he is.
Yes, Master.
You're such a fool.
Had you behaved, you might
have lived to see Doomsday.
But I must say, I am pleased.
For now, I have an opportunity to
fulfill another of my master's wishes.
Doctor, you won't believe this,
are you going to tell me that
someone is here from the outside?
Oh, yeah, it's been a
long time, but he's back.
So, Brad, have you ever met him before?
Well, yeah, I have, but I
was just a kid back then.
This will be the first time
you've met a real legend.
He's changed over the years.
Come with me.
So he really is back, what do you know?
Amazing how many years has it been
since I last opened this door?
Is he there is that him?
What do you mean?
You're telling me now I can't come in?
Who do you think you are,
you needle-logging idiot?
Ow!
Oh, hey, Doc.
Is that your great legend?
Is that rule him, huh?
What a relief.
He hasn't changed at all.
Your name's Brad, isn't it?
Man, you sure got taller.
Yeah, right.
By the way, who's he?
You know, to tell you the
truth, I'm not really sure.
Look,
I don't mind you wandering around the
place, but outsiders are not welcome here.
Oh, then I'll be like that big guy.
Okay.
Don't stare. Come on inside.
Get used to it. You win. I'll behave.
Huh? Huh?
Huh?
Fast!
Oh!
Gee, this is all rather
sudden, young lady.
I may have a reputation of being easy,
but even I need a bit of advanced warning.
Jessica! That's right! Wow!
I can't believe you remembered me!
This is the best date ever!
Well, Vash, this must
be your girlfriend, huh?
You are one lucky devil.
What's the matter?
Did I embarrass you?
Sorry, but I have to speak with
the doctor for a little while.
Hey!
Now that's not fair! Jessica!
Come see me after, okay?
Like right after?
I'll hate you if you don't.
OK, all right.
I'll be back in a minute.
So, Vash, how's Max? Is he well?
Oh, yeah, he's doing great.
He has staring contests
with forecast charts.
Huh?
Hmm, well, now, I haven't
introduced myself.
My name is Wolf Wa -
Can you blame her?
The people who live on
this ship aren't about
to trust a bunch of
outsiders bringing in war?
and violence.
You make this place stink like gunpowder.
Stay put until he gets back.
I don't want any trouble. Got that?
You could at least offer
me a drink or something.
For crying out loud, I am not the
least bit happy about this Millie.
We have just found him again,
and then we let him slip right
out from under our noses.
I know all that, but
we can't go out there.
It's too dangerous.
We have to, and besides,
danger is part of the job.
An entire city is surrounded
by lost technology.
I'm saying it to you little
by little, needle noggin.
Get out of here, mister!
I'm so sorry, but he's right.
I hate to say it, but I
feel the same way he does.
I'm begging you for the good of all of us.
Please leave this place.
Why, so you can all just carry on with
your perfect cozy little shuffle of lives?
Huh?
You need to realize your
plants are not inexhaustible.
They could very easily
break down some day.
You can't cling on to them forever.
This technology has a finite lifespan.
What are you telling us?
You have no idea how hard it
is to maintain these systems.
We're not planning on anything
shutting down for a long time now.
And anything's better
than living out there.
I've heard that people's
lives are meaningless to you,
so why should we listen to
anything you have to say?
Yeah, that's right!
No matter what you say, it's
not gonna change anything.
You better get used to
the idea that someday
you're gonna all live
on that desert planet.
Anything new happen while I was away?
No, not much.
They're still sleeping
in suspended animation.
Really?
We were all worried sick.
You've been out of touch
for nearly five years.
I'm sorry.
Sure.
Like you even care.
Five years is probably nothing more
than the blink of an eye for you anyway.
That's enough, Brad.
Vash is not that kind of person.
Person?
You gotta be kidding.
Since you have returned, I suppose
that means it's not over yet.
Did you come into contact with him
during the fifth moon incident?
Not directly, but my guess would be
that he had something to do with it.
I have absolutely no memory of it happening,
just like the time before in July.
Tell me, Vash.
Did you fire it?
Hey, Mr. Legend!
Since you're the one that
fired off the big weapon,
doesn't that make you more
destructive than knives?
I said enough, Brad!
Well, doesn't it? Brad!
That's right.
I suppose it does.
That is not funny.
That is not funny!
It's the whole damn world
we're talking about here.
Don't you think I am aware of that?
However,
the only one who has been able
to oppose knives fight off his
demons and survive them is that
gentleman holding by the neck?
I'm asking you to please trust me!
Please?
I'm sorry.
He's right.
I can't blame him.
Too simple and ordinary people,
I must seem like a monster.
Well, that's half his problem.
He's hopelessly in love with Jessica,
and he just told her for the first time.
Jessica.
I'm sorry, Brad, but
I'm going to marry back.
I'm getting very fast! Fast! Fast!
Well, that's the other
half of Brad's problem.
What's in there?
A little something you might be needing.
He hasn't been much fun,
but I'm sure glad he's back.
At least he hasn't changed.
He hasn't changed a bit.
Hey, Matt!
Wait!
Wait for me!
Look at me! Look at me! I'm in love!
This damn ship is full of nothing
but rotten, ignorant people.
Doesn't anyone trust the
word of a priest anymore?
Hey, up and up in there!
What's going on what's wrong
what the hell's going on in there
I mean, it was exactly
like this when I got here.
Hey, listen to me! What happened?
Brad, it's Terry and Natasha.
It was me, Brad.
I'm asking you to please trust me.
There's no way you can
prove your innocence!
This is great, Doc.
It's by far the smoothest one yet.
I'm glad you like it.
Now, we'd better hurry.
It's gotten very late.
Jessica will be furious with you.
Strange.
She said she would be here.
Oh, yes, that present.
She wanted to give it to you.
She's been looking forward to your
return for quite some time now.
Doc, what is this?
I'll say it one more
time, I didn't kill him.
Shut up, you're a killer
and a liar, Outsider!
You're serious, aren't you?
You really want to fight me, huh?
Hey, what are you doing?
Joseph! Move it!
You did this, didn't you?
Back off now, Brad.
You couldn't possibly survive a
fight against this breed of bad guy.
The warm-out fight, I presume?
Oh, so you know my name.
Well, I must say I mind.
I'm afraid we've never met,
but I have heard of you.
An interesting reputation.
You are the man who rings the black
funeral bell, chapel... Don't say it!
Enough with your butts!
This is just a warm-up,
both for him and for me.
You are smart, Preacher.
It would be easy to destroy you at
this point, but that would be boring.
To make the game more
interesting, I've added a sweet L.
Jessica!
I have been watching you through
his eyes the entire time.
I know that you have very strong
feelings for this young lady.
Very touching.
You do know what I have
in mind, do you not?
You pacifistic fool, don't
you realize this is a trap?
I know what it is.
Then lower your piece.
I can't.
I just don't see any way
out of this damn situation!
There is another way.
If we simply ignore the girl's plight,
we'll definitely make it through.
What did you say?
I think that's the best
option at this point in time.
It's the only logical way any
of us will survive against them.
No, you can't!
However,
I do know of a guy who whines,
cries, and throws tantrums,
and he somehow manages to
find a way to save everyone.
He's a crazy man who's
not afraid of anything.
Even though he's been scarred from
head to toe, he'll always be there.
Jessica!
Jess, are you alright?
They didn't hurt you, did they?
I guess they didn't.
What took you so long?
A flower.
A red flower.
Isn't it beautiful?
They call this one a geranium.
There are many other
types of flowers on Earth
of all different colors
and shapes and sizes.
They hold a very special
place in people's hearts.
Can you eat them forever?
Some flowers can be eating.
Do you like flowers?
I love flowers, especially red ones.
You know, they can be very symbolic.
Even the tiniest flowers which brave the
elements behold a magnificent strength.
And Vash,
in the language of the flower, red geraniums
represent determination and courage.
Hey, wait a sec!
Where'd you get the red coat?
I don't believe it.
It's Vash the Stampede!
Oh, Vash! Vash! Vash!
I'm so scared!
Knock it off!
Come on, will you stop it?
You're not upset, are you?
You act like it's all over.
But let me assure you, some of
my children are still there.
Besides, did you really think that the
gung-ho guns only come to call one at a time?
What are you saying?
Three of them.
That is correct.
I have sent three demons.
They have arrived and will be
visiting you very soon. Welcome.
This is your big comeback
celebration by Ashton Stampede.
The blue sky in the middle of
the sky, the wind is the future.
The light of the day of the sky,
the light of the day?
Thank
you
so
much for watching.
I'll see you
next time.
There's something you can't give up,
there's something you want to protect.
There's a time you must take a stand,
no matter what kind of pain awaits us.
The man clad in the red coat
took up his gun once again,
in order to stop the sadness,
in order to stop the hate.
I keep the word of the red geranium,
which I was taught so long ago.
I keep the courage and
determination deep in my heart.